Hey everybody, welcome
to this content video
that will go over section
8.4 of the textbook,
stripping white space from
strings. I know nothing sounds more
enthralling than stripping white
space from strings. Here we go.
Sometimes strings will have
leading or trailing white
space and you can use the
built-in Python method
strip to get rid of that
white space. So for example,
you have a sentence like this.
Notice it's got the Python
tab character and a newline
character and then it says
this is a test string,
tab, tab, new line, if you were to
strip that then the output would
be this is a test string. There's
also L strip, which stands for
remove the left leading white
space, and R strip, which stands for
remove the R, the right trailing
white space, but there's no method
called chicken strip, so we're all
a little bit sad about that one.
Anyways, let's do a couple of examples.
So let's make a different
variable. We'll call it pi.
Set that equal to tab character.
We love tab character.
New line character,
tab character. And I'm also adding
like spaces in between them too.
We'll do new line and
then tab. And then 3.1415.
I don't know
All right, so if we print out pi, let's
just print it and see what it gives us,
3.1415 pi, all right, so then if
we were to print out pi.strip,
we would expect to see the leading
and trailing whitespaces, hang on,
I forgot parentheses,
we would expect to see the
leading and trailing whitespaces
gone, and they are, except
we still have a ton of spaces
in between the first part
of our string and the second
part of our string. Why is
that? Well, it's because those
spaces are not leading or
trailing. And so how do we
get rid of those spaces?
That's another content video.
But for now, that's all
you really need to know.
The R strip, L strip, and
I'll just throw those in here
really quick so that we can
see them. And I have a question
for you at the end of it all.
So give me like one second.
I guess we already did regular
strips. I'll make this L
strip, and then we'll do pi
.rstrip, and it'll print out pi.
Okay,
well I should have added more commenting.
so here's regular pi, and then
we printed out pi just completely
stripped and then we printed out
pi l strip with the the white space
on the left side removed and then
we printed out pi with the space
on the right removed so that's
this one and then we printed out
pi again so here's a question
for you pi again has all of its
leading and trailing white space
why is that well it's because of a
concept that we've talked about
called mutability so strings are
immutable which means they are sorry
yeah immutable, which means they
are not changeable. So when I do
all these functions and methods
to a string, the string is actually
not changed. If I was to do
something similar to a list, the
list would actually be changed. It
is mutable, but strings are
immutable. So if I wanted to actually
make this change permanent, I
could say pi equals pi dot strip,
and then I could print out pi,
and I would see that pi is now
this variable. But that's kind
of a new string that we've been,
that we've created, we aren't
changing that string from before,
we're just setting a new variable
equal to the string. So hopefully
that makes some sense and that's
all for this content video.